# **PEARL CHRISTIAN**

FRONT-END DEVELOPER &
FACILITATOR

### **CONTACT INFO**

- Nigeria
- +234 8152 583 776
- pearlchristian6@gmail.com
- pearly-c.github.io/portfolio
- in linkedin.com/in/pearl-christian
- **□** github.com/Pearly-c

### **EDUCATION**

2019-2019

NIIT

Benin City, Edo Sate

Diploma: Web Development

### 2012-2016

Ota,Ogun Sate

Bells University of Technology

Bachelor of Science : Industrial Chemistry

## SOFT SKILLS

Good communication

problem-solving

Team-work

Creativity

Willingness to learn

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An ambitious, problem-solving front-end web developer with a high level of experience working on multiple projects. Self-motivated, passionate and hardworking with a penchant for meeting deadlines.

Interested in a role with a well-established organization that appreciates dedication and hardwork. Available to work remotely.

## **WORK HISTORY**

08/2021 - CURRENT

#### **EMPOWER HER COMMUNITY**

#### **ENGINEERING LEAD**

- Collaborate with team members to identify and fix technical problems.
- Delegate tasks/assignments to team members.
- Generate monthly status reports that clearly reflects all accomplishments in a given month.

02/2021 - CURRENT

### MIDTOWN TECH HUB

## FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

- Build reusable code for future use, while striking a balance between functional and aesthetic design.
- Ensure web design is optimized for smartphones.
- Ensure brand consistency is maintained throughout design, while optimizing web pages for maximum speed and scalability.
- Perform detailed code review to improve code quality.
- Participate in training beginners in front-end web development.

05/2020 - 11/2020

### **SIGHT INNOVATION**

## **WEB DEVELOPER INTERN**

- Develop ideas for new programs by monitoring industry trends.
- Evaluate code to ensure it's properly structured, meets industry standards and compatible with browsers and devices.
- Participate in training beginners in back-end web development.

01/2017 - 11/2017

## **MATTHIAS ACADEMY**

## TUTOR

- Prepare Lecture notes.
- Conduct assigned classes at the scheduled time.

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

**ReactJS** 

Javascript

Git version control/Github

Responsive web design

Web performance optimization

HTML/CSS/Bootstrap